He made a bet. She made history.
Battle of the Sexes is a drama, comedy, history film directed by Valerie Faris.
The true story of the 1973 tennis match between world number one Billie
Jean King and ex-champ and serial hustler Bobby Riggs.
Billie Jean King, played by Emma Stone.
Bobby Riggs, played by Steve Carell.
Marilyn Barnett, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Gladys Heldman, played by Sarah Silverman.
Jack Kramer, played by Bill Pullman.
Priscilla Riggs, played by Elisabeth Shue.
Battle of the Sexes is a 2017 sports comedy-drama film directed by Valerie
Faris and Jonathan Dayton and written by Simon Beaufoy.
The plot is loosely based on the 1973 tennis match
between Billie Jean King and Bobby Riggs.
The film stars Emma Stone and Steve Carell as King and Riggs, leading an ensemble cast including Andrea Riseborough, Elisabeth
Shue, Austin Stowell, Bill Pullman, Natalie Morales, Eric Christian Olsen, and Sarah Silverman in supporting roles.
The film marks the second collaboration between Carell and Stone after Crazy, Stupid, Love
and the second collaboration between Riseborough and Stone after Birdman.
The film had its premiere at the 44th Telluride Film Festival on September 2, 2017, and was
theatrically released in the United States by Fox Searchlight Pictures on September 22, 2017.
It received positive reviews from critics, who praised the performances of Stone and Carell
and the direction, with some calling it the best performance of Stone's career.
Despite the positive reviews, the picture performed poorly at the box
office, grossing $18.6 million against a $25 million budget.
At the 75th Golden Globe Awards, Stone and Carell received nominations for Best Actress – Motion
Picture Musical or Comedy and Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy respectively.
Both received Critics Choice Awards nominations in the categories
Best Actress in a Comedy and Best Actor in a Comedy.
At the 24th Screen Actors Guild Awards, Carell received a nomination for
Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Supporting Role.
The film explores themes of sports, tennis, 1970s, tennis player, biography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.